Heath, Cheston L. mss. ca. 1931-1947 LMC 2730
Lilly Library
Heath, Cheston L. mss.
1931-1947
Lilly Library
Heath, Cheston L.
LMC 2730
2.5 linear feet 2 boxes
The Heath, Cheston mss., ca. 1931-1947, consists of photographs and correspondence describing the wartime experiences of Cheston Heath, organist and choirmaster at Christ Episcopal Church in Indianapolis, Indiana for twenty-one years. The collection also contains Xeroxed copies of two of Heath's original compositions.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Organist and choirmaster at Christ Church Cathedral in Indianapolis, Indiana, for twenty one years. Cheston L. Heath was born in Corpus Christi, Texas, and directed his first choir at the age of fourteen. A year later, he entered the New England Conservatory of Music, and went on to earn an M.A. degree from Harvard University. After graduation, he traveled through Rome, Paris and Vienna, studying choral music and organ from Camille Saint-Saëns and Alexandre Guilmant. He is reported to have trained over a thousand choirboys for his choir and also was widely known for his musical compositions. During the St. Louis exposition, he was recognized as one of the seven greatest organists in the world. Heath died on February 11, 1947 at the age of 61.
Scope and Content Note
Collection consists of photographs and correspondence describing the wartime experiences of Cheston Heath, along with Xeroxed copies of two of Heath's original compositions. The correspondence in the collection is mainly from former choirboys of Heath's serving overseas (1943-1945). Additionally, there are oversized photocopies of choir music featuring original compositions bearing Heath's initials ("CLH").
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2009
World War, 1939-1945 --Personal narratives, American --Correspondence.; Organists -- Indiana -- Correspondence; Choral conductors -- Indiana -- Correspondence; Heath, Cheston L. --Correspondence.
- Collection (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1943, September-October (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1943, October-December (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1944, March-August (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1944, August (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1944, October (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1944, November-December (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1944, December-1945, April (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1945, May-August (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1945, August-October (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1945, October-November (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and photograph, undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and photograph, undated (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, programs, guild card, undated (Box 1)
  - "Register of Visitors, and Record of Flowers", undated (Box 1)
  - Sheet music, original Cheston L. Heath choir music, (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1945-1947 (Box 2)